<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL032017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>3</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>9A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170621 07:00:00 PM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170622 12:00:00 AM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201706220000</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0700 PM CDT Wed Jun 21</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1498089600</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>CINDY</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>28.3</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-93.3</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>28.3N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>93.3W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>50</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>85</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>45</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>992</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.29</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NW OR 315 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>8</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>13</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>7</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 125 MI...200 KM S OF LAKE CHARLES LOUISIANA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 115 MI...185 KM SE OF GALVESTON TEXAS</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT3 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Cindy Intermediate Advisory Number 9A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL032017
700 PM CDT Wed Jun 21 2017

...HEAVY RAINFALL CONTINUES TO AFFECT THE NORTHERN GULF COAST...
...THESE RAINS COULD PRODUCE LIFE-THREATENING FLASH FLOODING...


SUMMARY OF 700 PM CDT...0000 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...28.3N 93.3W
ABOUT 125 MI...200 KM S OF LAKE CHARLES LOUISIANA
ABOUT 115 MI...185 KM SE OF GALVESTON TEXAS
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...50 MPH...85 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NW OR 315 DEGREES AT 8 MPH...13 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...992 MB...29.29 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* San Luis Pass Texas to the mouth of the Mississippi River

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area, in this case within the
next 12 to 24 hours.

Interests elsewhere along the U.S. Gulf Coast from the central Texas
coast to the western Florida Panhandle should monitor the progress
of this system.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 700 PM CDT (0000 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Cindy was
located near latitude 28.3 North, longitude 93.3 West. Cindy is
moving toward the northwest near 8 mph (13 km/h).  A turn toward the
north-northwest is expected tonight and Thursday, with a turn toward
the northeast expected on Friday.  On the forecast track, the center
of Cindy will move inland over southeastern Texas or southwestern
Louisiana early Thursday, then move near or over extreme eastern
Texas, western and northern Louisiana, and southeastern Arkansas
Thursday and Thursday night.

Maximum sustained winds are near 50 mph (85 km/h) with higher
gusts. Little change in strength is expected before landfall, with
weakening expected thereafter. An elevated oil platform located
southwest of the center recently reported a wind gust of 75 mph.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 115 miles (185 km)
from the center.

The estimated minimum central pressure based on recent observations
from oil rigs near the center is 992 mb (29.29 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Cindy is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
6 to 9 inches with isolated maximum amounts up to 15 inches over
southeastern Louisiana, southern Mississippi, southern Alabama, and
western portions of the Florida Panhandle through Thursday night.
This rainfall could cause life-threatening flash flooding in these
areas.

Rainfall amounts of 3 to 5 inches with isolated maximum amounts of
7 inches can be expected farther west across western Louisiana and
eastern Texas through Thursday night. Rainfall should spread
northeastward across Arkansas and into portions of the Tennessee
and Ohio Valleys through Friday, with total rain accumulations of
3 to 5 inches with locally higher amounts possible.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions should spread westward and
northward through the Tropical Storm Warning area this evening
through Thursday.

STORM SURGE:  Inundation of 1 to 3 feet above ground level is
expected along the coast in portions of the Tropical Storm Warning
area. Inundation of 1 to 3 feet above ground level is also possible
elsewhere along the coast from southeastern Louisiana to the western
Florida Panhandle in areas of strong onshore winds.

TORNADOES:  A few tornadoes are possible tonight from the far
western Florida Panhandle across southwestern Alabama, southern
Mississippi, and southern Louisiana.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1000 PM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Stewart

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
