<?xml version="1.0"?>
<cycloneMessage>
<!-- System Advisory Meta Information -->
<atcfID>AL032017</atcfID>
<issuingUnit>NWS NATIONAL HURRICANE CENTER MIAMI FL</issuingUnit>
<messageType>INTERMEDIATE ADVISORY</messageType>
<messageBinNumber>3</messageBinNumber>
<advisoryNumber>7A</advisoryNumber>
<!-- System Date/Time Information -->
<messageDateTimeLocal>20170621 07:00:00 AM CDT</messageDateTimeLocal>
<messageDateTimeUTC>20170621 12:00:00 PM UTC</messageDateTimeUTC>
<messageDateTimeUTC24>201706211200</messageDateTimeUTC24>
<messageDateTimeLocalStr>0700 AM CDT Wed Jun 21</messageDateTimeLocalStr>
<timeEpochSeconds>1498046400</timeEpochSeconds>
<!-- System state defined -->
<systemType>TROPICAL STORM</systemType>
<systemName>CINDY</systemName>
<!-- Center Location of the System -->
<!-- Lattitude: North is positive; South is negative -->
<!-- Longitude: East is positive; West is negative -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitude>27.5</centerLocLatitude>
<centerLocLongitude>-92.2</centerLocLongitude>
<!-- Lattitude: North is N; South is S -->
<!-- Longitude: East is E; West is W -->
<!-- units: decimal degrees (tenths) -->
<centerLocLatitudeExpanded>27.5N</centerLocLatitudeExpanded>
<centerLocLongitudeExpanded>92.2W</centerLocLongitudeExpanded>
<!-- Maximum Intensity of the System -->
<!-- units: MPH, KPH, KTS, MB and/or INCHES HG -->
<systemIntensityMph>60</systemIntensityMph>
<systemIntensityKph>95</systemIntensityKph>
<systemIntensityKts>50</systemIntensityKts>
<systemMslpMb>996</systemMslpMb>
<systemMslpInHg>29.41</systemMslpInHg>
<systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>N/A</systemSaffirSimpsonCategory>
<formationChancePct48h>N/A</formationChancePct48h>
<formationChancePct5d>N/A</formationChancePct5d>
<!-- Current System Movement -->
<!-- units: Degrees, MPH and KPH -->
<systemDirectionOfMotion>NW OR 310 DEGREES</systemDirectionOfMotion>
<systemSpeedMph>8</systemSpeedMph>
<systemSpeedKph>13</systemSpeedKph>
<systemSpeedKts>7</systemSpeedKts>
<!-- Current System Location from known Reference Point -->
<systemGeoRefPt1>ABOUT 165 MI...265 KM SSW OF MORGAN CITY LOUISIANA</systemGeoRefPt1>
<systemGeoRefPt2>ABOUT 200 MI...325 KM SE OF GALVESTON TEXAS</systemGeoRefPt2>
<!-- Relevant Message -->
<message>
ZCZC MIATCPAT3 ALL
TTAA00 KNHC DDHHMM

BULLETIN
Tropical Storm Cindy Intermediate Advisory Number 7A
NWS National Hurricane Center Miami FL       AL032017
700 AM CDT Wed Jun 21 2017

...HEAVY RAINFALL COULD PRODUCE LIFE-THREATENING FLASH FLOODING
ACROSS PORTIONS OF THE NORTHERN GULF COAST...


SUMMARY OF 700 AM CDT...1200 UTC...INFORMATION
----------------------------------------------
LOCATION...27.5N 92.2W
ABOUT 165 MI...265 KM SSW OF MORGAN CITY LOUISIANA
ABOUT 200 MI...325 KM SE OF GALVESTON TEXAS
MAXIMUM SUSTAINED WINDS...60 MPH...95 KM/H
PRESENT MOVEMENT...NW OR 310 DEGREES AT 8 MPH...13 KM/H
MINIMUM CENTRAL PRESSURE...996 MB...29.41 INCHES


WATCHES AND WARNINGS
--------------------
CHANGES WITH THIS ADVISORY:

None.

SUMMARY OF WATCHES AND WARNINGS IN EFFECT:

A Tropical Storm Warning is in effect for...
* San Luis Pass Texas to the Alabama-Florida border
* Metropolitan New Orleans
* Lake Pontchartrain

A Tropical Storm Warning means that tropical storm conditions are
expected somewhere within the warning area, in this case within the
next 12 to 24 hours.

Interests elsewhere along the U.S. Gulf Coast from the central Texas
coast to the western Florida Panhandle should monitor the progress
of this system.

For storm information specific to your area, including possible
inland watches and warnings, please monitor products issued by your
local National Weather Service forecast office.


DISCUSSION AND 48-HOUR OUTLOOK
------------------------------
At 700 AM CDT (1200 UTC), the center of Tropical Storm Cindy was
located near latitude 27.5 North, longitude 92.2 West. Cindy is
moving toward the northwest near 8 mph (13 km/h), and this motion is
expected to continue today.  A turn toward the north-northwest and
then toward the north is expected later today and early Thursday. On
the forecast track, the center of Cindy will approach the coast of
southwest Louisiana and southeast Texas late today or tonight, and
move inland over southeastern Texas or southwestern Louisiana on
Thursday.

Maximum sustained winds remain near 60 mph (95 km/h) with higher
gusts. Little change in strength is expected today.  Slight
weakening is forecast to begin on Thursday.

Tropical-storm-force winds extend outward up to 275 miles (445 km),
mainly north through northeast of the center.

The minimum central pressure recently reported by an Air Force
Hurricane Hunter aircraft was 996 mb (29.41 inches).


HAZARDS AFFECTING LAND
----------------------
RAINFALL:  Cindy is expected to produce total rain accumulations of
6 to 9 inches with isolated maximum amounts of 12 inches over
southeastern Louisiana, southern Mississippi, southern Alabama, and
the Florida Panhandle through Thursday.  This rainfall could cause
life-threatening flash flooding in these areas.

Rainfall amounts of 3 to 5 inches with isolated maximum amounts of 6
inches can be expected farther west across western Louisiana and
eastern Texas through Thursday.  Rainfall should spread
northeastward across Arkansas and into portions of the Tennessee and
Ohio Valleys through Friday, with total rain accumulations of 3 to 5
inches with locally higher amounts possible.

WIND:  Tropical storm conditions are affecting portions of the
northern Gulf of Mexico coast over the eastern part of the warning
area.  These conditions should spread westward within the warning
area through early Thursday.

STORM SURGE:  Inundation of 1 to 3 feet above ground level is
expected along the coast in portions of the Tropical Storm Warning
area, with isolated areas possibly up to 4 feet.

TORNADOES:  A few tornadoes are possible this morning through
tonight from the western Florida Panhandle to southern Louisiana.


NEXT ADVISORY
-------------
Next complete advisory at 1000 AM CDT.

$$
Forecaster Avila

NNNN

</message>
</cycloneMessage>
